As you can see, this is a very different brush.
This is called either a foundation or concealer brush and it's a smooth palette and the bristles are very close.
So, they're very, very, almost feels like they're wet feeling, and this is concealer.
And as you can see, the concealer is a little bit whiter than her natural skin tone, and that's sometimes what you want to do.
You don't want to go too light though, or you don't want to go where it's too dark because concealer is used to bring out features in the face.
And usually concealer is not used over the entire face.
It's just used to cover up different things like under the eyes.
This covers up as we call it, those skunk eyes...raccoon eyes is what I mean.
Raccoon eyes.
And you go ahead and, well actually, sometimes I like to do, is use my own hand as a palette because the heat of my hand will melt the concealer just a little bit better so it goes on just a little bit smoother.
As you can see, I put quite a lot on the back of my hand.
Go ahead and put it underneath her eyes, and like I said, this goes ahead and gives you the appearance of not only taking away those imperfections underneath the eyes, but it also pops out certain bone structures in your face because you do want to pop out those high cheek bones, and this is exactly what this does when you use this.
You want to pop out those cheek bones especially on stage because you want to give the appearance of having perfect bone structure, right?
So, how do we do that?
That's achieved through makeup.
Makeup does so many origins, and as you can see, I'm putting it right here on the base of her nose.
You want to go ahead and get it down.
And it's almost like a square, rectangular shape that I'm doing this in.
Make sure that it's very, very smoothed out and you don't want it clumpy and you want to make sure, and as you can see, I'm not...I'm not doing it in a way that I would be painting, I'm actually pushing down on it with a brush.
So you push down on it to get that nice perfect skin tone, and as you can see I went all the way up into this space right here with that concealer, and we're going to do that exact same thing on the other side of the face.
Right there on the nose, like I said.
And right up into the eye corners, as you also want it there.
And make sure that it's very nicely and evenly smoothed out.
There we go.